

RUI OLIVEIRA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ♥ BRAGA, PORTUGAL **♦** 914304402

• DETAILS •

Braga Portugal 914304402

rui.nbc.oliveira@gmail.com

Date / Place of birth 27/04/1999 Braga

> Nationality Portuguese

PORTFOLIO

www.linkedin.com/in/ruinbcoliveira

https://github.com/priest110 https://priest110.github.io/

° SKILLS °

Technical (Proficient): Java, Python, C/C++, Prolog, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, React, Vue, Strapi, SQL, NoSQL, Docker, Git, Bash, Linux

Technical (Familiar): C#, Haskell, PHP, Erlang

Soft: Leadership and Teamwork, Self-management, Good Communitcation, Critical Thinking, Creativity

HOBBIES

Sports (particularly football and chess)
Puzzles and lego
Music festivals
Reading classic novels

LANGUAGES

Gardening (especially Bonsai)

Portuguese

English

Spanish

PROFILE

A solution-oriented software engineer with initiative and experience managing small and large teams as a skilled and dedicated leader. With a thirst for knowledge and a determination to bring new ideas to life that will benefit others.

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant at INESC Technology and Science - Associate Laboratory

March 2022 — November 2022

Analyzed the existing solutions to the problem of scientific data management, with
a focus on the CKAN, EUDAT, and Magda systems. Following this evaluation, an
adaptation of the most interesting (CKAN) was applied to a specific study, the SAIL
Project, an initiative promoted by INESC TEC researchers.

Vice President of Fiscal Council at Centro de Estudantes de Engenharia Informática da Universidade do Minho (CESIUM)

October 2018 — September 2019

- Promoted and managed CESIUM's connection with other entities in the academic community.
- Supported the development of events such as the "Semana da Engenharia Informática (SEI)" or the "Jornadas de Informática (JOIN)".

EDUCATION

Master's in Computer and Software Engineering, University of Minho

September 2017 — December 2022

- Specialization in Distributed Systems and Distributed Parallel Computing.
- Thesis: Scientific Data Management.

→ EXTRACURRICULAR

Member of the Green Lab Department at Society Loving the Planet Minho

January 2023 — Present

- Developed innovative and sustainable projects, such as "Nautilus", a device that calculates the water flow used in showers, with the goal of raising awareness about the amount of water consumed.
- Organized second-hand fairs with the municipality of Braga.

Director of the Strategy & Sustainable Development Department at Society Loving the Planet Minho

January 2022 — December 2022

- Managed the work of department members (4) on internal and external partner development.
- Initiated a program with the Sé elementary school, whose main goal was to provide children with sustainability and ecology sessions on thematic days.

Member of the Strategy & Sustainable Development Department at Society Loving the Planet Minho

May 2020 — December 2021

 Created and maintained internal university partners such as student centers, nuclei, and junior enterprises.

Vice President at Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

October 2017 — September 2018

- Helped manage the activities of the association, which had more than 40 members.
- Collaborated with the "Instituto Português do Desporto e Juvenitude (IPDJ)" and the municipality of Braga to promote and finance charitable projects as well as the organization's internal operations.

Board Member at Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

October 2015 — September 2017

 Promoted community service events in conjunction with organizations like the "Banco Alimentar".

★ VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer at Acolmax, Braga

June 2015 — Present

 Contributed to the provision of annual summer vacations for deprived children in Portugal (in places such as Costa da Caparica, Póvoa de Varzim, Castelo de Neiva, or Vila Praia de Âncora).

Mentor at Grupo de Jovens Alvorada, Braga

October 2019 — September 2022

Mentored 15-16 years old in weekly discussions about the world, with the goal
of creating a space for them to argue and, more importantly, to stimulate their
thinking.

COURSES

UEFA C Coach, Associação de Futebol de Braga

December 2022 — Present

Lifeguard, Delfins ENSP

March 2019 — May 2019

First Aid, Delfins ENSP

March 2019 — May 2019